Survival Resilience Redemption
Unbroken is a drama, war film directed by Angelina Jolie.
A chronicle of the life of Louis Zamperini, an Olympic runner who was
taken prisoner by Japanese forces during World War II.
Louis Zamperini, played by Jack O'Connell.
Pete Zamperini, played by Alex Russell.
Russel Allen 'Phil' Phillips, played by Domhnall Gleeson.
John Fitzgerald, played by Garrett Hedlund.
Mutsuhiro 'The Bird' Watanabe, played by MIYAVI.
Francis 'Mac' McNamara, played by Finn Wittrock.
Unbroken is a 2014 American war drama film produced and directed by Angelina Jolie and
written by the Coen brothers, Richard LaGravenese, and William Nicholson.
It is based on the non-fiction book by Laura Hillenbrand, Unbroken: A World
War II Story of Survival, Resilience, and Redemption (2010).
The film stars Jack O'Connell as Army officer Louis "Louie" Zamperini, an American
Olympian, and Miyavi as Imperial Japanese Army (IJA) corporal Mutsuhiro Watanabe.
Zamperini survived in a raft for 47 days after his bomber ditched in the ocean during the Second World War,
before being captured by the Japanese and being sent to a series of prisoner of war camps.
Filming took place in Australia from October 2013 to February 2014.
Unbroken had its world premiere in Sydney on November 17, 2014, followed by a
London premiere at the Odeon Leicester Square on November 26, 2014.
The film was released in the United States on December 25, 2014.
It received mixed reviews from critics, though praise was given to
O'Connell's performance and Deakins's cinematography.
It was a financial success, grossing $163 million worldwide.
The film was followed by a less succesfull sequel,
Unbroken: Path to Redemption, in 2018.
The film explores themes of japan, berlin, germany, based
on novel or book, sports, world war ii.
The tone is emotional.